I'm a technical leader and entrepreneur with a PhD in computer science, specialized in rendering, who has led projects to launch in both the games and the web3 industries. I have 12+ years of experience programming games and game engines in C++, including commercial work with Unreal Engine, 2 years of experience developing smart contracts for Cosmos, and 4+ years of technical leadership.

Contact & Personal Details

Location:	Vancouver, BC, Canada	Phone Number:	+12363347740
	(willing to relocate and work remotely)	Website:	www.drcisco.com (portfolio)
E-mail:	francisco@drcisco.com	Driving License:	Full (clean)
Credited:	Elite Dangerous, Planet Coaster, Jurassic World Evolution, Squad		

Work Experience

Date	Occupation	Employer
11/2021 – now CTO & Co-Founder: Neptune Finance, Smart Contracts in Rust		Cryptech, Canada
11/2018 – 11/2021	Senior/Lead Engineer: UE4, networked ragdolls, core tech project	Offworld Industries,
11/2018 - 11/2021	owner, led Squad through release and after.	Canada
12/2017 – 11/2018 <u>Software Engineer</u> : Rendering and skeleton animation. Interim CTO. Ososim, UK		Ososim, UK
11/2015 – 12/2017	Engine/Render Programmer: DX12, XB1, PS4, engine and rendering.	Frontier Developments, UK
09/2012 – 05/2015 <u>Lab Demonstrator</u> : Instructing BSc/MSc students in C++ and graphics. University of Hull, UK		University of Hull, UK

Education & Training

Date	Title	Institution	
2012-2017	PhD in Interactive Computer Graphics University of Hull, UK		Finished
"Reducing Geometry-Processing Overhead for Novel Viewpoint Creation" SIGGRAPH 2015			
2011-2012	MSc in Games Programming University of Hull, UK		Distinction
2008-2011	BSc in Computer Science	NOVA University of Lisbon, Portugal	16 of 20

Skills & Competences				
Languages	• English (fluent)	Portuguese (fluent)	Spanish (fluent)	• French (basic)
Platforms	• Windows	Xbox One	• PS4 & Cell (PS3)	• Linux & OSX
Fields	 Computer Graphics 	• Physics	 Networking 	 Unreal Engine 4
	 Cross-Platform 	 Software Engineering 	 Algorithm Analysis 	 Compilers
	 Artificial Intelligence 	 Multi-threading 	 Smart Contracts 	Research & Dev
Proficiency	C++, C#, C, Java, Rust, GLSL, HLSL, Cg, Typescript, Python, Jam, Prolog, HTML5, CSS3 OpenGL, DX11, DX12, CosmWasm			
Workflow	 Excellent task organisation and planning skills, through sprint planning, planning poker, creation of roadmaps, retrospectives and use of task management systems like JIRA, Notion, Linear, and Trello Proven ability to meet deadlines and work under pressure Version control experience in large shared code bases (SVN, P4, Git) and build systems (TeamCity) 			
Technical	 Blockchain and smart contract development experience Cross-platform game engine programming experience (PS3, XB1, PS4, OSX and PC) and UE4 Affinity and interest for solving problems and for abstract and top level thinking Experience with resource compilation in various formats for models, rigging and animation. 			
Soft Skills	Peer-recognized leade	startup founding experien rship and motivational ski	lls	
	 Great communication 	skills, including teaching ar	nd public presentations (S	IGGRAPH 2015 Poster)

Achievements

Date	Description
2012	Awarded a PhD scholarship at University of Hull
2011	Best final year undergraduate project by Opensoft and offered a merit scholarship